Mengqi Wang wmq516@gmail.com (801) 550-9772 Salt Lake City, UT

Web Developer GitHub LinkedIn Portfolio

Summary

Full stack web developer experienced in mobile-first development standards and modern web development workflow, with a technical focus on HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React.js, Vue.js, Node.js and algorithms & data structures. Strong background in education, event coordination and outreach.

Skills

Front-End: JavaScript ES6, React, Vue, Vuex, jQuery, Angular, Bootstrap-Vue, HTML5, CSS3, SASS

Back-End: Node.js, PostgreSQL, Express, Firebase, Python

Additional Skills & Tools: RESTful APIs, unit testing, algorithms, data structures, continuous integration, Git, GitHub, NPM, Mocha, Chai, Jest, Enzyme, Heroku

Experience

Frame Proposal

Salt Lake City, UT

Software Developer Intern

September 2020 – Present

- Built or refactored 18 (~55%) responsive front-end Vue and Bootstrap-Vue components, such as customer profile, creating customers, messaging components.
- Created 25 (~92%) test suites for the front-end components, raising test coverage from ~20% to 80%. Created 11 (~85%) test suites for data models, raising test coverage to ~95%.
- Maintained an organized modern web development workflow with Git, Github, Kanban boards, and a CI/CD pipeline.
- Collaborated with senior devs and product manager in weekly standup, code review and design decision making.

Just Utah Coders

Salt Lake City, UT

March 2020 – August 2020

Software Developer Volunteer

- Quickly on board and contributed to <u>utahexpungements.org</u> with minimal supervision.
- Addressed <u>70% (12/17)</u> and <u>88% (22/25)</u> of two issue collections compiled by Salt Lake County Expungement Coordinator.

Confucius Institute, University of Utah

Salt Lake City, UT

K-12 Outreach Coordinator

July 2019 – Present

- Developed six partnerships (e.g., with Salt Lake City Public Library and Utah Film Center) that led to actual programming, such as, teacher training, EDI training, scholarship info sessions, film screening and etc..
- Created new online programming and a marketing workflow that led to attendance above 50 people, with some events doubling regular attendance.

Recent Projects

Everest International Education | GitHub

- "Your go-to for teaching jobs in China"
- I, as the Product Owner, led a team of four and contributed 50% of the commits to this site.
- Tech: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript ES6, React, Node, PostgreSQL, Express

Open Garden | GitHub

- "Share extra homegrown vegetables and fruits with your neighbors"
- I conceptualized this project and built the site by myself in about 3 weeks.
- Tech: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Node, PostgreSQL, Express

ForDrizzle | GitHub

- "Enter your address and we will tell you whether you need to water your garden" team project
- Tech: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery

Country Capital Quiz | GitHub

- "Test your knowledge on countries' capitals!" team project
- Tech: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery

Education

THINKFUL December 2019

Full Stack Flex

- Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React, Redux, and algorithms & data structures.
- Created and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks by collaborating several hours every week with a senior web developer.

UNIVERSITY OF UTAH

MA in Linguistics, Syntax, GPA 3.96

July 2015

- Teaching Assistant for multiple linguistic courses
- Conference Presentation: Evidence on wh-head movement for Mandarin predicate cleft. 2015 Montral-Ottawa-Toronto-Hamilton Syntax Workshop, University of Ottawa, Canada